<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-10-20T22:12:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Weekly Review Checklist</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/10/20/our-weekly-review-checklist.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/10/20/our-weekly-review-checklist.html</id>
    <published>2014-10-20T22:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-22T18:13:18-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="our-weekly-review-checklist"&gt;Our Weekly Review Checklist&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Recurring Processes&lt;/b&gt;, that's where it's at for checklists.  At Manifestly, we have a Weekly Review process to keep track of where we are at, as a company.  Of course, this is a &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;Weekly Review Checklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you'd like to see or use the checklist we use each Monday for our Weekly Review, we've published it publicly &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basics steps of our checklist (which &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;you can copy&lt;/a&gt;) are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review Tasks and Plans (marketing &amp;amp; dev)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers &amp;amp; Analytics Review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blog &amp;amp; Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Are We Feeling?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set Goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have this checklist scheduled to run every Monday at 4pm.  We both receive an email from Manifestly with a link to the checklist.  It's kinda great. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="here-are-the-7-tools-we-use"&gt;Here are the 7 tools we use…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="google-docs"&gt;1. Google Docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used for tracking &lt;b&gt;Stretch Goals&lt;/b&gt;, ideas for &lt;b&gt;Blog Articles&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Growth Targets&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use google docs quite a bit.  For our weekly review, we start by reviewing our &lt;b&gt;stretch goals&lt;/b&gt; from the previous week.  We keep these stretch goals in google docs because of the simplicity (and history).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a document for our growth targets.  We're taking a tip from a &lt;a href="http://paulgraham.com/ds.html"&gt;Paul Graham blog post&lt;/a&gt; and we're focusing on work that &lt;b&gt;does not scale&lt;/b&gt; (you read that correctly).  We have created a spreadsheet with a very slow, but consistent growth target and we're comparing our growth with these targets each week.  So far, so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="trello"&gt;2. Trello&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href="http://trello.com"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; to manage our &lt;b&gt;marketing related&lt;/b&gt; tasks and plans.  Trello is a great tool for project management for teams.  We've attempted to use &lt;a href="http://asana.com"&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt; in the past, but the simplicity of Trello won out over the more full featured Asana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people have wondered if Trello is a competitor of Manifestly.  We don't think it is.  Trello is focused more on project management and ad hoc tasks (like our Marketing tasks), while we are &lt;b&gt;focused&lt;/b&gt; highly on simple &lt;b&gt;recurring processes&lt;/b&gt;.  There is plenty of room for both and it would be difficult to use Trello for something like a Daily Store Closing checklist. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pivotal-tracker"&gt;3. Pivotal Tracker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PT is used strictly for the &lt;b&gt;software development&lt;/b&gt; aspect of our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great tool for software developers.  We've both been using &lt;a href="http://pivotaltracker.com"&gt;Pivotal Tracker&lt;/a&gt; for years and although there are other tools out there for tracking development tasks, we don't actually consider them when starting a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pivotal Tracker is just easy, solid, and known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our weekly checklist, we look at the current iteration, the backlog, and the icebox.  We keep PT stories updated continuously during the week, so this review is mostly about prioritization of stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="intercom"&gt;4. Intercom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intercom is used to track &lt;b&gt;users and customers&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I (Philip) do most of the customer interaction work for Manifestly and I cannot say enough about how great &lt;a href="http://intercom.io"&gt;Intercom&lt;/a&gt; is for web based businesses.  Really, if you have a SaaS business and aren't using Intercom, you should definitely check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Monday during our weekly review, we look at our customer list in Intercom which shows data about engagement, new customers, and our onboarding messaging.  We use these facts to talk about who I will reach out to in order to help, as well as things we can do for the automated onboarding process - some of which is implemented via the &lt;a href="http://docs.intercom.io/faqs/should-i-send-auto-or-manual-message"&gt;nifty Intercom messages system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intercom is &lt;b&gt;fantastic&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="google-analytics"&gt;5. Google Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the goog for &lt;b&gt;analytics&lt;/b&gt; primarily because we've used it in the past and it is simple.  This is the tool we're least thrilled about.  Not because it isn't great, but more because we just don't know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts and recommendations on analytics are welcome, but for the current moment most of our analytics come from actually talking directly with our users.  In the future (with some scale), I suspect a decent approach to analytics will become more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our weekly review, we look at user flow and goals mostly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="github-pages-for-blogging"&gt;6. GitHub Pages for Blogging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our blog is published using &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.  It's kinda geeky and we're looking for a more simple publishing platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our weekly review, we look at the google document of blog ideas, add any if we think of them, and then look at the blog to check when the last post was published as well as any comments.  Our goal is 1-2 posts per month as features are released or we have something to share, like &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;this checklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="hootsuite-for-twitter"&gt;7. HootSuite for Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com"&gt;HootSuite&lt;/a&gt; for Twitter.  Most of our interaction on Twitter is with the Mac App, but for &lt;b&gt;scheduled tweets&lt;/b&gt; especially, we use HootSuite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our Monday review, we look at recent mentions and Twitter conversations as well as how long it has been since we last tweeted.  We might even do some searches to see if anyone has said anything about checklists and recurring processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="how-are-we-feeling"&gt;How Are We Feeling?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last steps in our weekly review are more about how we are feeling.  We discuss current mood as well as our goals moving forward and then finally we update our &lt;b&gt;stretch goals&lt;/b&gt; for the coming week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all done over a dinner at one of Madison's great restaurants like &lt;a href="http://www.grazemadison.com/"&gt;Graze&lt;/a&gt; or a beer at the UW Memorial Union Terrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this is helpful to other startups.  Our &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;Weekly Review Checklist&lt;/a&gt; has links directly to all of these services (our accounts, but you can change those) used in our weekly review.  Feel free to "fork" it and again, any suggestions are super welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–  Philip &amp;amp; Mark&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ps.  This is the University of Wisconsin Memorial Union Terrace.  It's pretty great.  :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/Union_terrace_night96_10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Checklists and To-Do lists are different</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/09/22/difference-checklists-todo-lists.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/09/22/difference-checklists-todo-lists.html</id>
    <published>2014-09-22T11:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-22T18:13:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="checklists-and-to-do-lists-are-different"&gt;Checklists and To-Do lists are different&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="right" width="200px" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/checklist.png" /&gt;
We talk with everyone we meet about checklists.  &lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt;.  What we've
found is a common misunderstanding about the &lt;strong&gt;subtle difference&lt;/strong&gt;
between checklists and to-do lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you're selling checklist software (like we are), the difference is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="checklists-are-how-to-do"&gt;Checklists are &lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checklists are best described as an agreement in an organization on &lt;strong&gt;How to Do&lt;/strong&gt; specific (important)
processes. They are codified "best practices" about how these processes
&lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be done. Examples from our customers include a
&lt;strong&gt;Daily Store Opening&lt;/strong&gt; checklist, &lt;strong&gt;New Client&lt;/strong&gt; checklist,
 &lt;strong&gt;Monthly Review&lt;/strong&gt; checklist, &lt;strong&gt;Listing a Property&lt;/strong&gt; checklist and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="to-do-lists-are-what-to-do"&gt;To-Do lists are &lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To-do lists, on the other hand, are unique, ephemeral (thankfully!), and ad hoc
in nature.  They are your list (or your team's list) of &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; you need to get done (today, this week, etc).
There are tons of tools for managing to-dos.  We have used &lt;a href="https://www.rememberthemilk.com/"&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.any.do"&gt;Any.do&lt;/a&gt;, and most recently we love &lt;a href="https://keep.google.com"&gt;Google Keep&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="instance-of-a-checklist-a-run-is-a-to-do-list"&gt;Instance of a Checklist (a run) is a To-do list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's where it gets interesting.  When you are &lt;strong&gt;using&lt;/strong&gt; a checklist, that is
effectively a to-do list.  Got that?  The thing you refer to when you're building up
a list of steps you want everyone to perform - that is a checklist.  When they use it, they're using
the checklist, but it is acting like a to-do list since it is a list of &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-does-this-matter"&gt;Why does this matter?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It matters because checklists are an important part of &lt;strong&gt;process improvement&lt;/strong&gt; activities.
By focusing on getting &lt;strong&gt;the right things done the right
way&lt;/strong&gt; - the &lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; - checklist are quality and consistency focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To-do lists don't provide this structure, nor do to-do list software solutions
focus on this continuous improvement process.  To-do lists focus on &lt;strong&gt;getting
things done&lt;/strong&gt;, especially at the individual productivity level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you haven't read &lt;a href="https://gawande.com/the-checklist-manifesto"&gt;The Checklist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;,
we often have some &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/about"&gt;free Checklist Manifesto copies&lt;/a&gt;
to give away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Checklists in Baseball</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/08/22/checklists-in-baseball.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/08/22/checklists-in-baseball.html</id>
    <published>2014-08-22T16:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-22T18:13:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="can-checklists-help-baseball-teams"&gt;Can Checklists Help Baseball Teams?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, Keith Law, &lt;a href="http://search.espn.go.com/keith-law"&gt;Senior Baseball Writer at ESPN.com&lt;/a&gt; thinks they might.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith is a &lt;a href="http://meadowparty.com/blog/2014/06/11/the-checklist-manifesto/"&gt;big fan of checklists&lt;/a&gt; and writes about them on his personal blog. He discovered the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Checklist-Manifesto-How-Things-Right-ebook/dp/B0030V0PEW"&gt;Checklist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; by reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00555X8OA/"&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt; - another excellent book we recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A major league team might have a checklist to use before acquiring any player in trade, for example – looking at recent reports and game logs to make sure he’s not injured, talking to a former coach or teammate to ensure there’s no character issues, etc. A well-designed blank scouting report is itself a checklist, a way of organizating information to also force the scout to answer the most important questions on each player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We agree! This could be part of an organization's more disciplined approach to data capture and analysis.  We've known for a long time that hiring (drafting) mistakes are very costly to any organization.  Anyone who has read or watched &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moneyball"&gt;Moneyball&lt;/a&gt; knows the importance of data in winning at the game of baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read Keith's full article on &lt;a href="http://meadowparty.com/blog/2014/06/11/the-checklist-manifesto/"&gt;checklists and baseball here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Restaurant Beta Users</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/06/02/restaurant-beta-users.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/06/02/restaurant-beta-users.html</id>
    <published>2014-06-02T16:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-22T18:13:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="restaurant-beta-users-we-need-you"&gt;Restaurant Beta Users, We Need You&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/The-Roman-Candle-Logo.png" align="right" /&gt;
We've been working on the use of checklists in restaurants with &lt;a href="http://theromancandle.com"&gt;The Roman Candle&lt;/a&gt;. TRC has been using Manifestly on their admin checklists and they're very happy thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many processes within restaurants that are golden opportunities for checklists, Daily Store Opening, Closing, Weekly reviews can all be better performed with a checklist software system like Manifestly.  We're excited to be working with TRC as they grow to more stores in Wisconsin and we congratulate them on their &lt;a href="http://theromancandle.com/milwaukee/"&gt;new restaurant in Milwaukee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any other restaurants, for a limited time we're offering our checklist service for free.  Forever.  Just contact us at &lt;a href="mailto:support@manifest.ly"&gt;support@manifest.ly&lt;/a&gt; to get started on using software to manage your &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly"&gt;restaurant checklists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scheduling Checklist Runs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/05/12/scheduling-checklist-runs.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/05/12/scheduling-checklist-runs.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-12T19:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-22T18:13:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="new-feature-scheduling-checklist-runs"&gt;New Feature: Scheduling Checklist Runs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a new feature that allows you to schedule your checklist runs. This is great if you have checklists that recur on any kind of schedule, whether it is daily, weekly, monthly - any kind of schedule can be set.  3rd Thursday?  No problem.  Last day of the month?  You bet.  Every other Tuesday?  Yep!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a few companies using this feature and we're quite sure most customers will find value from this ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add a new &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/scheduled_runs"&gt;scheduled checklist&lt;/a&gt; here if you are signed into your Manifestly account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/screen-shot-scheduled-runs.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New 'Explainer' Video</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/03/20/manifestly-video.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/03/20/manifestly-video.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-20T11:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-10-22T18:13:02-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="our-new-video-of-why-manifestly"&gt;Our New Video of 'Why Manifestly'&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've launched.  And, we have a video of the &lt;a href="https://manifest.ly"&gt;benefits of the Manifestly service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used &lt;a href="http://powtoon.com"&gt;PowToon&lt;/a&gt; to create the video.  We're impressed and found it very easy to use for this purpose.  We'll be using it for more 'explainer' type vides in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the new video we produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/rM4WdNmy7BM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
