<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-09-22T11:55:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Checklists and To-Do lists are different</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/09/22/difference-checklists-todo-lists.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/09/22/difference-checklists-todo-lists.html</id>
    <published>2014-09-22T11:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-24T11:10:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="checklists-and-to-do-lists-are-different"&gt;Checklists and To-Do lists are different&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="right" width="200px" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/checklist.png" /&gt;
We talk with everyone we meet about checklists.  &lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt;.  What we've
found is a common misunderstanding about the &lt;strong&gt;subtle difference&lt;/strong&gt;
between checklists and to-do lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you're selling checklist software (like we are), the difference is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="checklists-are-how-to-do"&gt;Checklists are &lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checklists are best described as an agreement in an organization on &lt;strong&gt;How to Do&lt;/strong&gt; specific (important)
processes. They are codified "best practices" about how these processes
&lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be done. Examples from our customers include a
&lt;strong&gt;Daily Store Opening&lt;/strong&gt; checklist, &lt;strong&gt;New Client&lt;/strong&gt; checklist,
 &lt;strong&gt;Monthly Review&lt;/strong&gt; checklist, &lt;strong&gt;Listing a Property&lt;/strong&gt; checklist and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="to-do-lists-are-what-to-do"&gt;To-Do lists are &lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To-do lists, on the other hand, are unique, ephemeral (thankfully!), and ad hoc
in nature.  They are your list (or your team's list) of &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; you need to get done (today, this week, etc).
There are tons of tools for managing to-dos.  We have used &lt;a href="https://www.rememberthemilk.com/"&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.any.do"&gt;Any.do&lt;/a&gt;, and most recently we love &lt;a href="https://keep.google.com"&gt;Google Keep&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="instance-of-a-checklist-a-run-is-a-to-do-list"&gt;Instance of a Checklist (a run) is a To-do list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's where it gets interesting.  When you are &lt;strong&gt;using&lt;/strong&gt; a checklist, that is
effectively a to-do list.  Got that?  The thing you refer to when you're building up
a list of steps you want everyone to perform - that is a checklist.  When they use it, they're using
the checklist, but it is acting like a to-do list since it is a list of &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-does-this-matter"&gt;Why does this matter?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It matters because checklists are an important part of &lt;strong&gt;process improvement&lt;/strong&gt; activities.
By focusing on getting &lt;strong&gt;the right things done the right
way&lt;/strong&gt; - the &lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; - checklist are quality and consistency focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To-do lists don't provide this structure, nor do to-do list software solutions
focus on this continuous improvement process.  To-do lists focus on &lt;strong&gt;getting
things done&lt;/strong&gt;, especially at the individual productivity level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you haven't read &lt;a href="https://gawande.com/the-checklist-manifesto"&gt;The Checklist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;,
we often have some &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/about"&gt;free Checklist Manifesto copies&lt;/a&gt;
to give away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Checklists in Baseball</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/08/22/checklists-in-baseball.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/08/22/checklists-in-baseball.html</id>
    <published>2014-08-22T16:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-23T16:52:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="can-checklists-help-baseball-teams"&gt;Can Checklists Help Baseball Teams?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, Keith Law, &lt;a href="http://search.espn.go.com/keith-law"&gt;Senior Baseball Writer at ESPN.com&lt;/a&gt; thinks they might.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith is a &lt;a href="http://meadowparty.com/blog/2014/06/11/the-checklist-manifesto/"&gt;big fan of checklists&lt;/a&gt; and writes about them on his personal blog. He discovered the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Checklist-Manifesto-How-Things-Right-ebook/dp/B0030V0PEW"&gt;Checklist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; by reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00555X8OA/"&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt; - another excellent book we recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A major league team might have a checklist to use before acquiring any player in trade, for example – looking at recent reports and game logs to make sure he’s not injured, talking to a former coach or teammate to ensure there’s no character issues, etc. A well-designed blank scouting report is itself a checklist, a way of organizating information to also force the scout to answer the most important questions on each player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We agree! This could be part of an organization's more disciplined approach to data capture and analysis.  We've known for a long time that hiring (drafting) mistakes are very costly to any organization.  Anyone who has read or watched &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moneyball"&gt;Moneyball&lt;/a&gt; knows the importance of data in winning at the game of baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read Keith's full article on &lt;a href="http://meadowparty.com/blog/2014/06/11/the-checklist-manifesto/"&gt;checklists and baseball here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Restaurant Beta Users</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/06/02/restaurant-beta-users.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/06/02/restaurant-beta-users.html</id>
    <published>2014-06-02T16:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-23T16:52:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="restaurant-beta-users-we-need-you"&gt;Restaurant Beta Users, We Need You&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/The-Roman-Candle-Logo.png" align="right" /&gt;
We've been working on the use of checklists in restaurants with &lt;a href="http://theromancandle.com"&gt;The Roman Candle&lt;/a&gt;. TRC has been using Manifestly on their admin checklists and they're very happy thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many processes within restaurants that are golden opportunities for checklists, Daily Store Opening, Closing, Weekly reviews can all be better performed with a checklist software system like Manifestly.  We're excited to be working with TRC as they grow to more stores in Wisconsin and we congratulate them on their &lt;a href="http://theromancandle.com/milwaukee/"&gt;new restaurant in Milwaukee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any other restaurants, for a limited time we're offering our checklist service for free.  Forever.  Just contact us at &lt;a href="mailto:support@manifest.ly"&gt;support@manifest.ly&lt;/a&gt; to get started on using software to manage your &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly"&gt;restaurant checklists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Scheduling Checklist Runs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/05/12/scheduling-checklist-runs.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/05/12/scheduling-checklist-runs.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-12T19:32:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-23T16:52:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="new-feature-scheduling-checklist-runs"&gt;New Feature: Scheduling Checklist Runs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a new feature that allows you to schedule your checklist runs. This is great if you have checklists that recur on any kind of schedule, whether it is daily, weekly, monthly - any kind of schedule can be set.  3rd Thursday?  No problem.  Last day of the month?  You bet.  Every other Tuesday?  Yep!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a few companies using this feature and we're quite sure most customers will find value from this ability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add a new &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/scheduled_runs"&gt;scheduled checklist&lt;/a&gt; here if you are signed into your Manifestly account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/screen-shot-scheduled-runs.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>New 'Explainer' Video</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/03/20/manifestly-video.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/03/20/manifestly-video.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-20T11:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-23T16:52:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="our-new-video-of-why-manifestly"&gt;Our New Video of 'Why Manifestly'&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've launched.  And, we have a video of the &lt;a href="https://manifest.ly"&gt;benefits of the Manifestly service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used &lt;a href="http://powtoon.com"&gt;PowToon&lt;/a&gt; to create the video.  We're impressed and found it very easy to use for this purpose.  We'll be using it for more 'explainer' type vides in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's the new video we produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/rM4WdNmy7BM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Now with comments!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/02/26/comments.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/02/26/comments.html</id>
    <published>2014-02-26T01:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-23T16:52:21-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id="our-blog-allows-comments"&gt;Our Blog Allows Comments!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, not exactly the blog post we &lt;a href="/2014/01/20/live.html"&gt;wished&lt;/a&gt; we could write today, but little steps. Eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are &lt;a href="/2013/10/08/looking-for-ux-designer.html"&gt;still looking for a designer as a partner&lt;/a&gt; and meanwhile have managed to put together a reasonably functional UX.  With a solid designer though, we think the experience would be much, much better.  So, please share this link - it would help tremendously!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, we're very close to launching.  Very, very close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
