<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-02-28T21:12:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Third Party Integrations, Now in Beta</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/02/28/third-party-integrations-beta.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/02/28/third-party-integrations-beta.html</id>
    <published>2015-02-28T21:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-01T10:03:16-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We now have integrations with many other services, including the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="integrations"&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/highrise.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/eventbrite.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/salesforce.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/survey_monkey.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/stripe.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/intercom.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/lighthouse.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/github.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="zapier"&gt;Zapier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manifestly has partnered with &lt;a href="http://zapier.com"&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; to provide integrations between many popular web sites and Manifestly. There are now &lt;strong&gt;over 300 services&lt;/strong&gt; you can use as triggers for running manifestly checklists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="how-it-works"&gt;How it Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zapier works based on triggers and actions.  You can connect any number of services, including SalesForce, GitHub, Eventbrite, and hundreds of others.  Once connected, you can choose what &lt;strong&gt;triggers in those systems&lt;/strong&gt; (for example, a new order on Eventbrite) cause a &lt;strong&gt;checklist to be run&lt;/strong&gt; in Manifestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="col-md-3 zapier-logos text-center"&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;An change here&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/zendesk.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/intercom.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/airbrake.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/github.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/shopify.png" /&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/storenvy.png" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-3 text-center"&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;Causes&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/arrow-right.jpg" height="80px" /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-3 text-center"&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;A Checklist Run&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/manifestly.png" /&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Zapier has &lt;a href="https://zapier.com/zapbook/"&gt;excellent documentation&lt;/a&gt; on using Zaps to automate your business workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="examples"&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new user in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/intercom.png" height="25px" /&gt; causes a checklist run in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/manifestly.png" height="25px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new issue in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/github.png" height="25px" /&gt; causes a checklist run in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/manifestly.png" height="25px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A ticket sold in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/eventbrite.png" height="25px" /&gt; causes a checklist run in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/manifestly.png" height="25px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A product sold in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/shopify.png" height="25px" /&gt; causes a checklist run in &lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/zapier/manifestly.png" height="25px" /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="in-beta-contact-us-to-get-started"&gt;In Beta, Contact Us to get Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature is currently in beta, so please email us at &lt;a href="mailto:support@manifest.ly"&gt;support@manifest.ly&lt;/a&gt; to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Checklists as a Continuous Improvement Tool</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2015/01/04/checklists-and-continuous-improvement.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2015/01/04/checklists-and-continuous-improvement.html</id>
    <published>2015-01-04T14:31:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-01T10:02:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many people write about using checklists as a &lt;strong&gt;one-way process&lt;/strong&gt;, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/use_checklist_basic.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where the role of a checklist is to &lt;strong&gt;ensure conformance&lt;/strong&gt; to the desired process, usually determined by people other than those using the checklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one-way communication is missing out on a valuable opportunity to engage people who are using the checklist to &lt;strong&gt;provide ideas for improvement&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="plan--do--check--act"&gt;Plan &amp;gt; Do &amp;gt; Check &amp;gt; Act&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are familiar with the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PDCA"&gt;Plan&amp;gt;Do&amp;gt;Check&amp;gt;Act&lt;/a&gt; continuous improvement process made popular by W. Edwards Deming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7a/PDCA_Cycle.svg/2000px-PDCA_Cycle.svg.png" width="400px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="its-continuous"&gt;It's Continuous&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most obvious difference PDCA has from the diagram at the top of this post is that it is &lt;strong&gt;continuous&lt;/strong&gt; and benefits from &lt;strong&gt;iterations&lt;/strong&gt; of doing and analyzing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="six-sigma"&gt;Six Sigma&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more recently developed process improvement methodology is &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Six_Sigma"&gt;Six Sigma&lt;/a&gt; and is data driven approach to &lt;em&gt;eliminating defects in any process&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/sixsigma.jpg" width="400px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="iterative"&gt;Iterative!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again of note is the &lt;strong&gt;continuous cycle of improvement&lt;/strong&gt; and analysis built into this methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="iterations-iterations-iterations"&gt;Iterations, Iterations, Iterations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with building software, iterations are the key to creating useful checklists.  Here's what Atul Gawande said about the first version of the famous surgery checklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The checklist was too long. It was unclear. And past a certain point, it was starting to feel like a distraction from the person we had on the table.
By the end of the day, we had stopped using the checklist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several versions later however the surgery checklist became a world wide hospital tool and the &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=122226184"&gt;average number of complications and deaths dipped by 35 percent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the best way to gather ideas to be used in a continuous improvement process?  &lt;strong&gt;Ask questions&lt;/strong&gt;.  And &lt;a href="/2014/11/28/effective-checklists.html"&gt;questions are an indicator of a good checklist&lt;/a&gt; as we wrote in our "Effective Checklists" article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="explicitly-ask-for-ideas"&gt;Explicitly Ask For Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All checklists should end with the same step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h1 id="do-you-have-ideas-for-improving-this-process"&gt;Do you have ideas for improving this process?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this simple step at the end of your checklists, you will gather more and better ideas for process improvement as well as signal to your staff that their ideas matter (and so does the checklist).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="good-checklists-respect--engage"&gt;Good Checklists Respect &amp;amp; Engage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some final thoughts on checklists from the &lt;a href="http://atulgawande.com/book/the-checklist-manifesto/"&gt;Checklist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="good-checklists"&gt;Good checklists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“… do not try to spell out everything – a checklist cannot fly a plane.  Instead, they provide reminders of only the most critical and important steps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="bad-checklists"&gt;Bad checklists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“They treat people using the tools as dumb and try to spell out every single step.  They turn people’s brains off rather than turn them on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What Makes a Checklist Effective?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/11/28/effective-checklists.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/11/28/effective-checklists.html</id>
    <published>2014-11-28T23:31:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-01T10:02:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/"&gt;Manifestly&lt;/a&gt;, we're dedicated to helping people use
checklists to improve their recurring processes. In this article, we're going to
dive into the question of what makes a checklist effective by focusing on these
questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is a checklist?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What kinds of processes lend themselves best to the use of a checklist?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What makes a checklist effective?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-is-a-checklist"&gt;What is a checklist?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've written about this before, noting &lt;a href="http://blog.manifest.ly/2014/09/22/difference-checklists-todo-lists.html"&gt;the difference between checklists and
TODO lists&lt;/a&gt;.
The key difference is that the purpose of a checklist is to
highlight key decision points or risks that require communication and
collaboration among the team members using the checklist. A checklist tool–such
as &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/"&gt;Manifestly&lt;/a&gt;–enables such communication and
collaboration in real-time, and serves as a record of the decisions and
communication that took place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pro Tip:  If your checklist enumerates every single step of the underlying
process, you're probably doing it wrong. Imagine you have a store opening
checklist for a restaurant. And one of the steps is, "Take the chairs off the
tables and put them on the floor." It won't take long before the people using
such a checklist every day completely checkout from using the checklist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-kinds-of-processes-lend-themselves-best-to-the-use-of-a-checklist"&gt;What kinds of processes lend themselves best to the use of a checklist?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A checklist is all about highlighting key decision points, key checkpoints, key
risks, and facilitating communication and collaboration among the team
addressing these items. If you have a recurring process that involves no
decisions, no risks, and requires no communication–then it's probably not
a great candidate for the use of a checklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have many recurring processes in your organization. Which of these are
best suited for a checklist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How frequently do the people using the checklist perform the process?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much collaboration is involved in the process?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How complex is the process? Are there important decision points? Are there
real risks that need to be evaluated?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-makes-a-checklist-effective"&gt;What makes a checklist effective?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It flows pretty naturally from what we've already covered, that an effective
checklist is one that facilitates good decisions. Good decisions naturally flow
from good conversation. And what enables conversation better than good
questions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Pro Tip: If your checklist is full of questions, you're probably doing it right.
Imagine a store opening checklist that ends with, “Would you invite your friends
to join you to eat at this restaurant?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An effective checklist is first a checklist, not something else. Checklists are
best used with recurring processes that involve a team collaboratively making
decisions in the midst of complexity and risk. Good checklists tend to ask
questions, which is the easiest way to get the collaborative juices flowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our next article, we'll looking at how you can take any checklist and improve
it over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Review Checklist for a SaaS Startup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/10/20/our-weekly-review-checklist.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/10/20/our-weekly-review-checklist.html</id>
    <published>2014-10-20T22:12:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-01T10:02:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;strong&gt;SaaS startup&lt;/strong&gt;, we need to continually make sure we're working on &lt;strong&gt;the most important things&lt;/strong&gt;.  And so, we have a weekly checklist to keep us focused and ensure we're moving forward on marketing, customer support, features, and financial goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've published it here: &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;SaaS Weekly Review Checklist&lt;/a&gt; and made it available to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The basics steps of our checklist (which &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;you can copy&lt;/a&gt;) are:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review Tasks and Plans (marketing &amp;amp; dev)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customers &amp;amp; Analytics Review&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blog &amp;amp; Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How Are We Feeling?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set Goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have this checklist scheduled to run every Monday at 4pm.  Mark &amp;amp; I both receive an email from Manifestly with a link to the checklist.  It's kinda great. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="here-are-the-7-tools-we-use"&gt;Here are the 7 tools we use…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id="google-docs"&gt;1. Google Docs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used for tracking &lt;b&gt;Stretch Goals&lt;/b&gt;, ideas for &lt;b&gt;Blog Articles&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Growth Targets&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use google docs quite a bit.  For our weekly review, we start by reviewing our &lt;b&gt;stretch goals&lt;/b&gt; from the previous week.  We keep these stretch goals in google docs because of the simplicity (and history).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a document for our growth targets.  We're taking a tip from a &lt;a href="http://paulgraham.com/ds.html"&gt;Paul Graham blog post&lt;/a&gt; and we're focusing on work that &lt;b&gt;does not scale&lt;/b&gt; (you read that correctly).  We have created a spreadsheet with a very slow, but consistent growth target and we're comparing our growth with these targets each week.  So far, so good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="trello"&gt;2. Trello&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href="http://trello.com"&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; to manage our &lt;b&gt;marketing related&lt;/b&gt; tasks and plans.  Trello is a great tool for project management for teams.  We've attempted to use &lt;a href="http://asana.com"&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt; in the past, but the simplicity of Trello won out over the more full featured Asana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people have wondered if Trello is a competitor of Manifestly.  We don't think it is.  Trello is focused more on project management and ad hoc tasks (like our Marketing tasks), while we are &lt;b&gt;focused&lt;/b&gt; highly on simple &lt;b&gt;recurring processes&lt;/b&gt;.  There is plenty of room for both and it would be difficult to use Trello for something like a Daily Store Closing checklist. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="pivotal-tracker"&gt;3. Pivotal Tracker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PT is used strictly for the &lt;b&gt;software development&lt;/b&gt; aspect of our business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a great tool for software developers.  We've both been using &lt;a href="http://pivotaltracker.com"&gt;Pivotal Tracker&lt;/a&gt; for years and although there are other tools out there for tracking development tasks, we don't actually consider them when starting a new project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pivotal Tracker is just easy, solid, and known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our weekly checklist, we look at the current iteration, the backlog, and the icebox.  We keep PT stories updated continuously during the week, so this review is mostly about prioritization of stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="intercom"&gt;4. Intercom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intercom is used to track &lt;b&gt;users and customers&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I (Philip) do most of the customer interaction work for Manifestly and I cannot say enough about how great &lt;a href="http://intercom.io"&gt;Intercom&lt;/a&gt; is for web based businesses.  Really, if you have a SaaS business and aren't using Intercom, you should definitely check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Monday during our weekly review, we look at our customer list in Intercom which shows data about engagement, new customers, and our onboarding messaging.  We use these facts to talk about who I will reach out to in order to help, as well as things we can do for the automated onboarding process - some of which is implemented via the &lt;a href="http://docs.intercom.io/faqs/should-i-send-auto-or-manual-message"&gt;nifty Intercom messages system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intercom is &lt;b&gt;fantastic&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="google-analytics"&gt;5. Google Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the goog for &lt;b&gt;analytics&lt;/b&gt; primarily because we've used it in the past and it is simple.  This is the tool we're least thrilled about.  Not because it isn't great, but more because we just don't know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts and recommendations on analytics are welcome, but for the current moment most of our analytics come from actually talking directly with our users.  In the future (with some scale), I suspect a decent approach to analytics will become more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our weekly review, we look at user flow and goals mostly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="github-pages-for-blogging"&gt;6. GitHub Pages for Blogging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our blog is published using &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.  It's kinda geeky and we're looking for a more simple publishing platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our weekly review, we look at the google document of blog ideas, add any if we think of them, and then look at the blog to check when the last post was published as well as any comments.  Our goal is 1-2 posts per month as features are released or we have something to share, like &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;this checklist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="hootsuite-for-twitter"&gt;7. HootSuite for Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href="http://hootsuite.com"&gt;HootSuite&lt;/a&gt; for Twitter.  Most of our interaction on Twitter is with the Mac App, but for &lt;b&gt;scheduled tweets&lt;/b&gt; especially, we use HootSuite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our Monday review, we look at recent mentions and Twitter conversations as well as how long it has been since we last tweeted.  We might even do some searches to see if anyone has said anything about checklists and recurring processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="how-are-we-feeling"&gt;How Are We Feeling?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last steps in our weekly review are more about how we are feeling.  We discuss current mood as well as our goals moving forward and then finally we update our &lt;b&gt;stretch goals&lt;/b&gt; for the coming week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all done over a dinner at one of Madison's great restaurants like &lt;a href="http://www.grazemadison.com/"&gt;Graze&lt;/a&gt; or a beer at the UW Memorial Union Terrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this is helpful to other startups.  Our &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/public/checklists/8d29833cdfdd634b41623c2e5abf511b"&gt;Weekly Review Checklist&lt;/a&gt; has links directly to all of these services (our accounts, but you can change those) used in our weekly review.  Feel free to "fork" it and again, any suggestions are super welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–  Philip &amp;amp; Mark&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ps.  This is the University of Wisconsin Memorial Union Terrace.  It's pretty great.  :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/Union_terrace_night96_10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Checklists and To-Do lists are different</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/09/22/difference-checklists-todo-lists.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/09/22/difference-checklists-todo-lists.html</id>
    <published>2014-09-22T11:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-01T10:02:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We talk with everyone we meet about checklists.  &lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt;.  What we've
found is a common misunderstanding about the &lt;strong&gt;subtle difference&lt;/strong&gt;
between checklists and to-do lists. And if you're selling checklist software (like we are), the difference is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align="right" width="200px" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/manifestly-assets/checklist.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="checklists-are-how-to-do"&gt;Checklists are &lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Checklists are best described as an agreement in an organization on &lt;strong&gt;How to Do&lt;/strong&gt; specific (important)
processes. They are codified "best practices" about how these processes
&lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be done. Examples from our customers include a
&lt;strong&gt;Daily Store Opening&lt;/strong&gt; checklist, &lt;strong&gt;New Client&lt;/strong&gt; checklist,
 &lt;strong&gt;Monthly Review&lt;/strong&gt; checklist, &lt;strong&gt;Listing a Property&lt;/strong&gt; checklist and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="to-do-lists-are-what-to-do"&gt;To-Do lists are &lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; To-Do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To-do lists, on the other hand, are unique, ephemeral (thankfully!), and ad hoc
in nature.  They are your list (or your team's list) of &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; you need to get done (today, this week, etc).
There are tons of tools for managing to-dos.  We have used &lt;a href="https://www.rememberthemilk.com/"&gt;Remember the Milk&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://www.any.do"&gt;Any.do&lt;/a&gt;, and most recently we love &lt;a href="https://keep.google.com"&gt;Google Keep&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="instance-of-a-checklist-a-run-is-a-to-do-list"&gt;Instance of a Checklist (a run) is a To-do list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's where it gets interesting.  When you are &lt;strong&gt;using&lt;/strong&gt; a checklist, that is
effectively a to-do list.  Got that?  The thing you refer to when you're building up
a list of steps you want everyone to perform - that is a checklist.  When they use it, they're using
the checklist, but it is acting like a to-do list since it is a list of &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="why-does-this-matter"&gt;Why does this matter?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It matters because checklists are an important part of &lt;strong&gt;process improvement&lt;/strong&gt; activities.
By focusing on getting &lt;strong&gt;the right things done the right
way&lt;/strong&gt; - the &lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; - checklist are quality and consistency focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To-do lists don't provide this structure, nor do to-do list software solutions
focus on this continuous improvement process.  To-do lists focus on &lt;strong&gt;getting
things done&lt;/strong&gt;, especially at the individual productivity level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you haven't read &lt;a href="https://gawande.com/the-checklist-manifesto"&gt;The Checklist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;,
we often have some &lt;a href="https://www.manifest.ly/about"&gt;free Checklist Manifesto copies&lt;/a&gt;
to give away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Can Checklists Help Baseball Teams?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/08/22/checklists-in-baseball.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/08/22/checklists-in-baseball.html</id>
    <published>2014-08-22T16:20:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-01T10:02:00-06:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, Keith Law, &lt;a href="http://search.espn.go.com/keith-law"&gt;Senior Baseball Writer at ESPN.com&lt;/a&gt; thinks they might.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith is a &lt;a href="http://meadowparty.com/blog/2014/06/11/the-checklist-manifesto/"&gt;big fan of checklists&lt;/a&gt; and writes about them on his personal blog. He discovered the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Checklist-Manifesto-How-Things-Right-ebook/dp/B0030V0PEW"&gt;Checklist Manifesto&lt;/a&gt; by reading &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00555X8OA/"&gt;Thinking, Fast and Slow&lt;/a&gt; - another excellent book we recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A major league team might have a checklist to use before acquiring any player in trade, for example – looking at recent reports and game logs to make sure he’s not injured, talking to a former coach or teammate to ensure there’s no character issues, etc. A well-designed blank scouting report is itself a checklist, a way of organizating information to also force the scout to answer the most important questions on each player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We agree! This could be part of an organization's more disciplined approach to data capture and analysis.  We've known for a long time that hiring (drafting) mistakes are very costly to any organization.  Anyone who has read or watched &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moneyball"&gt;Moneyball&lt;/a&gt; knows the importance of data in winning at the game of baseball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read Keith's full article on &lt;a href="http://meadowparty.com/blog/2014/06/11/the-checklist-manifesto/"&gt;checklists and baseball here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
